{"name": "C03 2019-12", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. A function, f, is defined by f(x,y) = 3x2 - 4y. What is the value of f(3,2) ?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "10", "C": "19", "D": "24", "E": "28"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. In the figure below, \u2220BAC measures 35\u00b0\uff0c\u2220ABC measures 95\u00b0, and points B, C, and D are collinear. What is the measure of \u2220ACD ?", "choices": {"A": "95\u00b0", "B": "125\u00b0", "C": "130\u00b0", "D": "140\u00b0", "E": "145\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. For all nonzero values of x and y, which of the following expressions is equivalent to   \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "-40x3y2 ", "B": "-32x3y2 ", "C": "-9x5y4 ", "D": "-9x4y3 ", "E": "-9x3y2 "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. At a certain airline company, the cost to transfer mileage points from one person's account to another person's account is $0.75 for every 100 mileage points transferred plus a onetime $20 processing fee. What is the cost to transfer 7, 000 mileage points from one account to another at that airline company?", "choices": {"A": "$25.25", "B": "$67.50", "C": "$72.50", "D": "$75.00", "E": "$95.00"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. For x = -5, what is the value of 4x2 - 11x ?", "choices": {"A": "-155", "B": "-84", "C": "-45", "D": "84", "E": "155"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. Taho earns his regular pay of $11 per hour for up to 40 hours of work per week. For each hour over 40 hours of work per week, Taho earns times  regular pay. How much does Taho earn in a week in which he works 50 hours?", "choices": {"A": "$550", "B": "$605", "C": "$625", "D": "$750", "E": "$825"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. A science class has 8 juniors and 4 seniors. The teacher will randomly select 2 students, one at a time, to represent the class in a committee at the school. Given that the first student selected is a junior, what is the probability that the second student selected will be a senior?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. When Tyrone fell asleep one night, the temperature was 24\u00b0 F. When Tyrone awoke the next morning, the temperature was -12\u00b0F. Letting + denote a rise in temperature and - denote a drop in temperature, what was the change in temperature from the time Tyrone fell asleep until the time he awoke?", "choices": {"A": "-36\u00b0F", "B": "-12\u00b0F", "C": "+6\u00b0F", "D": "+12\u00b0F", "E": " +36\u00b0F"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. The total cost of renting a car is $35.00 for each day the car is rented plus 42.5\u00a2 for each mile the car is driven. What is the total cost of renting the car for 6 days and driving 350 miles?(Note: No sales tax is involved.)", "choices": {"A": "$ 154.75", "B": "$ 224.88", "C": "$ 358.75", "D": "$ 420.00", "E": "$ 1,697.50"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, what is the slope of the line through (-6 4) and (1,3)?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. One morning at a coffee shop, each customer ordered either decaf or regular coffee, and each ordered it either with milk or without milk. The number of customers who ordered each type of coffee with or without milk is listed in the table below.A customer will be randomly selected from all 36 customers for a prize. What is the probability that the selected customer will have ordered a regular coffee without milk? ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. Which of the following inequalities describes the solution set for 3x - 5 &lt; 2x + 1 ?", "choices": {"A": "x \uff1c -4", "B": "-\\frac{4}{5}\" width=\"52\" height=\"32.6\">", "C": "", "D": "x \uff1c 6", "E": "x \uff1e 6"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. Which of the following expressions is equivalent to 4(x + 2) + 3(2x - 1) ?", "choices": {"A": "3x + 8", "B": "5(2x + 1)", "C": "10(x + 1)", "D": "10x + 11", "E": "15x"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. What is 4% of 1.36 \u00d7 104 ?", "choices": {"A": "340", "B": "544", "C": "3,400", "D": "5,440", "E": "54,400"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. What is the least common denominator of the fractions  , ,  and   \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "110", "B": "770", "C": "2,695", "D": "8,470", "E": "59,290"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. The point (3,27) is labeled on the graph of f(x) = x3 in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below. The graph of f(x) will be translated 3 coordinate units to the left. Which of the following points will be on the image of the graph after the translation?", "choices": {"A": "(0,27)", "B": "(3,24)", "C": "(3,27)", "D": "(3,30)", "E": "(6,27)"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, what is the midpoint of the line segment that has endpoints (-6,9) and (2,5)?", "choices": {"A": "(-4,-4)", "B": "(-2,7)", "C": "", "D": " (4,-2)", "E": "(8,-4)"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. What value of x satisfies the equation ", "choices": {"A": "-4", "B": "-3", "C": "-2", "D": "1", "E": "2"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. Use the following information to answer questions 19-21.A large theater complex surveyed 5,000 adults. The results of the survey are shown in the tables below.Tickets are $9.50 for all regular showings and $7.00 for matinees.19.\tBased on the survey results, what was the average number of moviegoers for each of the 4 categories?", "choices": {"A": "610", "B": "1,060", "C": "1,240", "D": "1,250", "E": "1,985"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. Use the following information to answer questions 19-21.A large theater complex surveyed 5,000 adults. The results of the survey are shown in the tables below.Tickets are $9.50 for all regular showings and $7.00 for matinees.20.\tSuppose all the adults surveyed happened to attend I movie each in one particular week. The total amount spent on tickets by those surveyed in that week was $44,000.00. How many adults attended matinees that week?", "choices": {"A": "500", "B": "1,400", "C": "2,500", "D": "3,600", "E": "4,500"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. Use the following information to answer questions 19-21.A large theater complex surveyed 5,000 adults. The results of the survey are shown in the tables below.Tickets are $9.50 for all regular showings and $7.00 for matinees.21. One of the following circle graphs represents the  proportion by age group of the adults surveyed. Which one?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. In the figure shown below, all angles are right angles, and the side lengths given are in centimeters. What is the area, in square centimeters, of the figure?", "choices": {"A": "42", "B": "75", "C": "93", "D": "99", "E": "117"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. In the figure below, E is on CA \uff0cand the measures of\u2220BED and \u2220AEB are 90\u00b0 and 145\u00b0, respectively. If it can be determined, what is the measure of \u2220CED ?", "choices": {"A": "35\u00b0", "B": "45\u00b0", "C": "55\u00b0", "D": "80\u00b0", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, the graph of the function y = 5 sin(x) -7 undergoes a  single  translation such  that of the the equation of its  image is y = 5 sin(x) - 14. Which of the following describes this translation ?", "choices": {"A": "Up 7 coordinate units", "B": "Down 7 coordinate units", "C": "Left  7 coordinate units", "D": "Right  7 coordinate units", "E": "Right  14 coordinate units"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. What is the value of  \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "7", "B": "25", "C": "49", "D": "337", "E": "625"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. A the right triangle is shown in the figure below. What is the value of sin?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. A 6-inch-by-6-inch squares grid shown below is divided into 36 squares, each with a side length of 1 inch. Each vertex of the 2 shaded  triangles lies at an intersection of 2 grid lines. What fractional part of the 6-inch-by-6-inch square is shaded ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. All values  in the the equation equation below are exact. What value of c makes the equation true?  ", "choices": {"A": "-7", "B": "-6.5", "C": "-5", "D": "-4.5", "E": "-4"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. Which of the following inequalities is true for all positive integers m ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. A formula for the volume, V, of a right circular cylinder is V = \u03c0r2h , where r is the radius and h is the height. The cylindrical tank shown below has radius 5 meters and height 3 meters and is filled with water.Given that the weight of 1 cubic meter of water is approximately 2,205 pounds, the weight, in pounds, of the water in the tank is:", "choices": {"A": " less than 200,000.", "B": "between 200,000 and 300,000.", "C": "between 300,000 and 500,000.", "D": "between 500,000 and 1,000,000.", "E": "more than 1,000,000. "}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. Graphed in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below is a right triangle with vertices (0,0), (-40,0), and (0,30). What is the length, in coordinate units, of the hypotenuse of the triangle?", "choices": {"A": "30", "B": "35", "C": "40", "D": "50", "E": "70"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. Every graph in one of the following categories has a vertical line of symmetry regardless of how it is oriented in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane. Which one?", "choices": {"A": "Circles", "B": "Squares", "C": "Elipses", "D": "Triangies", "E": "Rectangles"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, the graph of y = 30(x + 17)2 - 42 is a parabola. What are the coordinates of the vertex of the parabola?", "choices": {"A": "(-30,-42)", "B": "(-17,-42)", "C": "(17,-42)", "D": "(17, 42)", "E": "(30. 42)"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. One side of square ABCD has a length of 15 meters. A certain rectangle whose area is equal to the area of ABCD has a width of 10 meters. What is the length, in meters, of the rectangle?", "choices": {"A": "15", "B": "20", "C": "22.5", "D": "25", "E": "37.5"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. The average weight of 10 boys is 77.0 pounds. If the youngest boy is excluded, the average weight of the 9 remaining boys is 78.0 pounds. What is the weight, in pounds, of the youngest boy? ", "choices": {"A": "62", "B": "68", "C": "70", "D": "78", "E": "87"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. The total amount of a certain substance present in a laboratory experiment is given by the formula\uff0c where A is the total amount of the substance h hours after an initial amount (A0) of the substance began accumulating. Which of the following expressions gives the number of hours it will take an initial amount of 10 grams of this substance to accumulate to 100 grams?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "25", "C": "", "D": " ", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. For all values of x greater than 3, which of the following  expressions 1s equivalent to\uff1f", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. Shown below, a board 9 feet 4 inches long is cut into  2 equal parts. What is the length, to the nearest inch, of each part?", "choices": {"A": "4 feet 5 inches", "B": "4 feet 7 inches", "C": "4 feet 8 inches", "D": "5 feet 4 inches", "E": " 5 feet 5 inches"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. If the positive integers x and y are relatively prime (their greatest common factor is 1) and  , then ?", "choices": {"A": "23", "B": "25", "C": "49", "D": "91", "E": "132"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. What is the 358th digit after the decimal point in the repeating decimal 0.3178?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "3", "C": "1", "D": "7", "E": "8"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. To promote a new brand of shoes, a shoe store will run a promotion using a jar containing 3 red balls marked \"10% off,\" 2 white balls marked \"30% off,\" and I green ball marked \"60% off.\" Each customer will randomly select 1 ball from the jar to determine the discount that the customer will receive on any single pair of the new brand of shoes. Given that the new brand of shoes regularly costs $60 per pair, what is the average discount amount, in dollars, that the store can expect to give each customer due to this promotion?", "choices": {"A": "$6", "B": "$10", "C": "$15", "D": " $20", "E": "$25"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. Use the following information to answer questions 42-44.A 500-square-mile national park in Kenya has large and small protected animals. The number of  large protected animals at the beginning of 2014 is given in the table below.At the beginning of 2014, the number of all protected animals in the park was 10,000. Zoologists predict that for each year from 2015 to 2019, the total number of protected animals in the park at the beginning of the year will be 2% more than the number of protected animals in the park at the beginning of the previous year.42.\tAt the beginning of 2014, the number of lions in the park was p percent of the total number of large animals. Which of the following is closest to the value of p?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "8", "C": "9", "D": "11", "E": "12"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. Use the following information to answer questions 42-44. A 500-square-mile national park in Kenya has large and small protected animals. The number of  large protected animals at the beginning of 2014 is given in the table below.At the beginning of 2014, the number of all protected animals in the park was 10,000. Zoologists predict that for each year from 2015 to 2019, the total number of protected animals in the park at the beginning of the year will be 2% more than the number of protected animals in the park at the beginning of the previous year.43. In this park, the average number of gallons of water consumed per day by each elephant, lion, and  giraffe is 50, 5 and 10, respectively . Which of the following matrix products yields the average  total number  of gallons of water consumed per day by all the elephants, lions, and giraffes in the park?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. Use the following information to answer questions 42-44.A 500-square-mile national park in Kenya has large and small protected animals. The number of  large protected animals at the beginning of 2014 is given in the table below.At the beginning of 2014, the number of all protected animals in the park was 10,000. Zoologists predict that for each year from 2015 to 2019, the total number of protected animals in the park at the beginning of the year will be 2% more than the number of protected animals in the park at the beginning of the previous year.44.\tLet t  be a positive integer less than 6. Based on the zoologists' prediction, which of the following expressions represents the number of protected animals in the park t years after the beginning of 2014 ?", "choices": {"A": " 10,000 + 0.02t", "B": "10,000 + 0.2t", "C": "", "D": " ", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. Anela and Jacob plan to attend a concert in Brady. Anela will drive 375 km to Brady at a constant speed of 75 km/hr, stopping one time for a 30-minute break. Jacob will start 600 km from Brady and will drive at a constant speed of 90 km/hr for 2 hours. He will take a  1-\thour break and then drive to Brady at a constant speed of 70 km/hr.To the nearest 0.1 hour, Jacob must leave how much earlier than Anela in order for them to arrive in Brady at the same time?", "choices": {"A": "2.2", "B": "2.5", "C": "3.1", "D": "3.5", "E": "4.0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. Which of the following is equal to  , for all x 0  \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "-4x+8", "B": "-4x+2", "C": "-2x+1", "D": "", "E": "2"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. A rectangular stage is 90 feet long and 30 feet wide. What is the area, in square  yards, of this stage?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "300", "C": "675", "D": "900", "E": "2700"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. A rectangle, with its vertex coordinates labeled, is graphed in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below. A lattice point is a point with coordinates that are both integers. A  lattice point inside but NOT on the rectangle will be chosen at random. What is the probability that the sum of the x-coordinate and they-coordinate of the chosen lattice point will be odd?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. The  nth term of an arithmetic progression is given by the formula  , where  d is the common difference and  is the first term. If the third term of an arithmetic progression is and the sixth term is , what is the seventh term?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "0", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "1"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. The probability of Jamie being chosen to bat first in the lineup for his baseball team is  . What are the odds in favor of Jamie being chosen to bat first?(Note: The odds in favor of an event are defined as the ratio of the probability that the event will happen to the probability that the event will NOT happen.)", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. A 120-liter solution that is 5% salt is mixed with an 80-\tliter solution that is 15% salt. The combined solution is what percent salt?", "choices": {"A": "8%", "B": "9%", "C": "10%", "D": "11%", "E": "12%"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. A 50-foot-long rectangular swimming pool with vertical sides is 3 feet deep at the shallow end and 10  feet deep at the deep end. The bottom of the pool slopes downward at a constant angle from horizontal along the length of the pool. Which of the following expressions gives this constant angle? (Note: For \uff0c  y = tan x if and only if x=)", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. A hyperbola that has vertices (1,2) and (3,2) and that  passes through the origin is shown below in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane. The hyperbola has which of the following equations?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54.  As shown below, Alli walked her dog 250 feet due east from the entrance of a dog park to a trash can and then walked 700 feet in a straight line 25\u00b0 north of east to a bench. Which of the following expressions is equal to the distance, in feet, between the entrance and the bench?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. For real numbers a, b, and c such that a&gt;b &gt;c and b &gt; 0, which of the statements below is(are)  always true?I. lal &gt; lblII. lal &gt; lclIII. lbl &gt; lcl ", "choices": {"A": " I only", "B": "II only", "C": " I and II only", "D": "II and lII only", "E": "I, II, and III"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. Kenji and Mary are members of a school committee that will be meeting this afternoon. The 6 members of the committee will be seated randomly around a circular table. What is the probability that Kenji and Mary will NOT sit next to each other at the meeting?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. The digit in the ones place of  is 6. What is the digit in the ones place of ? ", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "2", "C": "4", "D": "6", "E": "8"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. Which of the following expressions represents the area, in square coordinate units, of \u25b3RST shown in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. In the complex numbers, where  = -1, what complex number x is a solution to the equation x(2 + 3\bi )= 1 ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "1", "D": "-1", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. The rectangular container shown below has a small compartment for water created by a rectangular dividing wall of negligible width. One face of the dividing wall, shown shaded, has an area of 39 square inches. What is the volume, in cubic inches, of the larger compartment?", "choices": {"A": "180", "B": "195", "C": "390", "D": "450", "E": "540"}, "correct": "D"}]}